What do I do if my doctor tells me I
need to donate blood, but I feel
completely fine for over four years?
Hemoglobin was at 18.7, hematocrit was
57.
>> I mean, that's going to be up to you and
how you comfortable you are standing up
to your provider. I wouldn't want to
joust with a provider. Um, a lot of
these people are very passionate about
where their stances are, even though
they have no clue about this topic. They
just that's just how they roll. That's
that's common in medicine. It's common
in life. People are dogmatic about
things they've never actually studied.
And so if they're cool with you doing
that, if they just sort of flippantly,
you know, recommend it, but then you're
like, "No, I'm good. I feel fine. I
don't think there's any issues." And
they're like, "Okay, well, that may be
fine." If they're like, "No, you have to
do this." To the point where they're
changing your dosing and withholding it,
find another doctor. Like there's no
reason for that four years heat 18s,
upper 50s. That's very common with guys
on TRT. And you know I just I was that
guy. I had a hemat hemoglobin in the 18s
and a hematocritic at 57 58. I felt fine
and I I didn't have any strokes or blood
clots or anything like that. Like so all
these people making claims about being
causitive just you're not seeing that in
reality. You can you can theoretically
think about that stuff all you want and
say well this could mechanism. It's like
no it doesn't matter. I can come up with
any explanation for it but it doesn't
matter if it's not true. So but back to
your question with the doctors. Yeah,
that's going to come down to the
personality of the doctor and how
comfortable you are. I mean, some people
want to literally joust with their
doctors and be like, "Oh, you claim
that. Well, give me backup for it. Show
me studies." They're not going to do
that. Those doctors are not going to go
look up stud. Most of them. Now, some
might, if they're open-minded, they
might go, "Oh, you know, that's a good
point. I don't actually know that. Let
me go look into it a little bit." Most
won't do that. Even if they do go look
into it, they won't know how to look
into it. they'll just go find some
abstracts and read them out and some
correlative studies and and just call it
as as fact. So, you you got to find the
right provider if you really want it uh
that's going to look deeper in these
things in an open-minded way and kind of
sometimes meet you in the middle on
these things because it really is about
that in the end. But they they have
their boundaries too and that's fine. If
you don't if they're set on their
boundaries, it's not right for us to
push try to push them over those
boundaries if they're not comfortable
just like guys do with me. Hey, if
they're like, "No, I you need to
prescribe an aromatase inhibitor." I'm
like, "You need to find another doctor
because that's my boundary. I am not
going to do it." So, either you live
without it or you do it on your own or
you go find somebody. And that's okay.
Like, we don't all have to agree. And I
don't I don't want people paying me who
don't agree with my philosophy on
things, right? Like that. That's that's
the beauty of the market and choices is
that we there's so many different ways.
So yeah, find somebody if you can who's
like-minded, but if you can find
somebody who's just cool and they're
like they're just throwing that out
there as a recommendation, but they're
not being like stickler about it, that's
probably fine, too.
>> Exactly.